<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
    xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
    <title>NBER Working Papers</title>
    <link>https://www.nber.org/papers</link>
    <description>Table of Contents for Econometrica. List of articles from both the latest and EarlyView issues.</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com (Wiley Online Library)</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 07:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 07:05:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
    <ttl>10080</ttl>
    <dc:title>NBER Working Papers</dc:title>
    <dc:publisher>National Bureau of Economic Research</dc:publisher>
    <prism:publicationName>NBER Working Papers</prism:publicationName>
    <atom:link href="https://www.nber.org/papers"
    rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><item><title>Permanent and Transitory Responses to Capital Gains Taxes: Evidence from a Lifetime Exemption in Canada</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Adam M Lavecchia, Alisa Tazhitdinova</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Permanent and Transitory Responses to Capital Gains Taxes: Evidence from a Lifetime Exemption in Canada</dc:title>
<dc:description>Using panel data on a 20% random sample of Canadian taxpayers, we study behavioral responses to the cancellation of a lifetime capital gains exemption that resulted in increased capital gains taxation for some individuals. The unique setting allows us to distinguish between short-term avoidance responses and permanent responses to capital gains taxes. We show that the exemption did not change the number of taxpayers reporting positive capital gains, and thus unlikely resulted in increased participation in capital markets. However, the exemption cancellation slightly increased capital gains realizations of the existing traders.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28514</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28514</prism:url></item><item><title>Estimating Students&#x27; Valuation for College Experiences</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Esteban M Aucejo, Jacob F French, Basit Zafar</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Estimating Students&#x27; Valuation for College Experiences</dc:title>
<dc:description>The college experience involves much more than credit hours and degrees. Students likely derive utility from in-person instruction and on-campus social activities. Quantitative measures of the value of these individual components have been hard to come by. Leveraging the COVID-19 shock, we elicit students’ intended likelihood of enrolling in higher education under different costs and possible states of the world. These states, which would have been unimaginable in the absence of the pandemic, vary in terms of class formats and restrictions to campus social life. We show how such data can be used to recover college student’s willingness-to-pay (WTP) for college-related activities in the absence of COVID-19, without parametric assumptions on the underlying heterogeneity in WTP. We find that the WTP for in-person instruction (relative to a remote format) represents around 4.2% of the average annual net cost of attending university, while the WTP for on-campus social activities is 8.1% of the average annual net costs. We also find large heterogeneity in WTP, which varies systematically across socioeconomic groups. Our analysis shows that economically-disadvantaged students derive substantially lower value from university social life, but this is primarily due to time and resource constraints.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28511</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28511</prism:url></item><item><title>Financial Regulation in a Quantitative Model of the Modern Banking System</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Juliane Begenau, Tim Landvoigt</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Financial Regulation in a Quantitative Model of the Modern Banking System</dc:title>
<dc:description>How does the shadow banking system respond to changes in capital regulation of commercial banks? We propose a quantitative general equilibrium model with regulated and unregulated banks to study the unintended consequences of regulation. Tighter capital requirements for regulated banks cause higher convenience yield on debt of all banks, leading to higher shadow bank leverage and a larger shadow banking sector. At the same time, tighter regulation eliminates the subsidies to commercial banks from deposit insurance, reducing the competitive pressures on shadow banks to take risks. The net effect is a safer financial system with more shadow banking. Calibrating the model to data on financial institutions in the U.S., the optimal capital requirement is around 16%.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28501</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28501</prism:url></item><item><title>Consumption Access and Agglomeration: Evidence from Smartphone Data</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Yuhei Miyauchi, Kentaro Nakajima, Stephen J Redding</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Consumption Access and Agglomeration: Evidence from Smartphone Data</dc:title>
<dc:description>We provide new theory and evidence on the role of consumption access in understanding the agglomeration of economic activity. We combine smartphone data that records user location every 5 minutes of the day with economic census data on the location of service-sector establishments to measure commuting and non-commuting trips within the Greater Tokyo metropolitan area. We show that non-commuting trips are frequent, more localized than commuting trips, strongly related to the availability of nontraded services, and occur along trip chains. Guided by these empirical findings, we develop a quantitative urban model that incorporates  travel to work and travel to consume non-traded services. Using the structure of the model, we estimate theoretically-consistent measures of travel access, and show that consumption access makes a sizable contribution relative to workplace access in explaining the observed variation in residents and land prices across locations. Undertaking counterfactuals for changes in travel costs, we show that abstracting from consumption trips leads to a substantial underestimate of the welfare gains from a transport improvement (because of the undercounting of trips) and leads to a distorted picture of changes in travel patterns within the city (because of the different geography of commuting and non-commuting trips).</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28497</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28497</prism:url></item><item><title>Limited-Tenure Concessions for Collective  Goods</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Nicolas Quérou, Agnes Tomini, Christopher Costello</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Limited-Tenure Concessions for Collective  Goods</dc:title>
<dc:description>We analyze theoretically an institution called a “limited-tenure concession” for its ability to induce efficient public goods contribution and common-pool resource extraction. The basic idea is that by limiting the tenure over which an agent can enjoy the public good, but offering the possibility of renewal contingent on ample private provision of that good, efficient provision may be induced. We first show in a simple repeated game setting that limited-tenure concessions can incentivize socially-efficient provision of public goods. We then analyze the ability of this instrument to incentivize the first best provision for common-pool natural resources such as fish and water, thus accounting for spatial connectivity and natural growth dynamics of the resource. The duration of tenure and the dispersal of the resource play pivotal roles in whether this limited-duration concession induces the socially optimal private provision. Finally, in a setting with costly monitoring, we discuss the features of a concession contract that ensure first-best behavior, but at least cost to the implementing agency.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28518</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28518</prism:url></item><item><title>School Assignment by Match Quality</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Atila Abdulkadiroglu, Umut M Dur, Aram Grigoryan</dc:creator>
<dc:title>School Assignment by Match Quality</dc:title>
<dc:description>Proponents of school choice argue that it improves educational outcomes by allowing parents to self-select into schools that are most effective for their children. Contrary to these arguments, empirical evidence suggests that parents may not incorporate school effectiveness or match quality when choosing schools. The findings potentially impugn proponents&#x27; effectiveness arguments of choice-based assignment. We develop novel solutions that restore effectiveness by maximizing match quality subject to stability constraints. Maximization algorithms are provided for both small and large school districts. Simulations reveal substantial match quality gains from our solutions compared to the celebrated Deferred Acceptance mechanism with a random tie-breaker. Our methodology can be used to optimize for other policy objectives in school choice or other priority-based matching problems.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28512</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28512</prism:url></item><item><title>Portfolios for Long-Term Investors</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>John H Cochrane</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Portfolios for Long-Term Investors</dc:title>
<dc:description>How should long-term investors form portfolios in our time-varying, multifactor and friction-filled world? Two conceptual frameworks may help: looking directly at the stream of payments that a portfolio and payout policy can produce, and including a general equilibrium view of the markets’ economic purpose, and the nature of investors’ differences. These perspectives can rationalize some of investors’ behaviors, suggest substantial revisions to standard portfolio theory, and help us to apply portfolio theory in a way that is practically useful for investors.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28513</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28513</prism:url></item><item><title>Intellectual Property Infringement by Foreign Firms: Import Protection through the ITC or Court</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>James A Brander, Barbara J Spencer</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Intellectual Property Infringement by Foreign Firms: Import Protection through the ITC or Court</dc:title>
<dc:description>This paper examines intellectual property litigation as a method of protection from patent-infringing imports. Claims against patent-infringing imports entering the United States may be filed before the International Trade Commission (ITC) or in district court. The ITC applies injunctions (import prohibitions) that would seem to provide more protection from infringing imports than the standard license fee remedy in court. Settlements prior to legal adjudication are common in both venues. Using a model with Nash bargaining and Cournot competition, we show that an ITC filing may restrict imports by less than in court. This result tends to apply if product differentiation is high and the size of the patented cost-reducing innovation is large.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28496</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28496</prism:url></item><item><title>Kidney Exchange: An Operations Perspective</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Itai Ashlagi, Alvin E Roth</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Kidney Exchange: An Operations Perspective</dc:title>
<dc:description>Many patients in need of a kidney transplant have a willing but incompatible (or poorly matched) living donor. Kidney exchange programs arrange exchanges among such patient-donor pairs, in cycles and chains of exchange, so each patient receives a compatible kidney. Kidney exchange has become a standard form of transplantation in the United States and a few other countries, in large part because of continued attention to the operational details that arose as obstacles were overcome and new obstacles became relevant. We review some of the key operational issues in the design of successful kidney exchange programs. Kidney exchange has yet to reach its full potential, and the paper further describes some open questions that we hope will continue to attract attention from researchers interested in the operational aspects of dynamic exchange.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28500</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28500</prism:url></item><item><title>Financial Regulation, Clientele Segmentation, and Stock Exchange Order Types</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Sida Li, Mao Ye, Miles Zheng</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Financial Regulation, Clientele Segmentation, and Stock Exchange Order Types</dc:title>
<dc:description>Financial regulations and clientele segmentation explain the proliferation of order types on stock exchanges. Plain market and limit orders lose money, indicating that informed traders use complex orders. Fifty-seven percent of trading volume comes from non-routable orders, which are designed to bypass Reg NMS. Because Reg NMS routes orders based on the best gross prices, it often routes orders to worse net prices after adjusting for fees. Non-routable orders win speed races to capture short-term profits, but all order types containing long-term information are routable. An order type that complies with share repurchase regulations earns a 30-day return of 7%.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28515</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28515</prism:url></item><item><title>Measuring Commuting and Economic Activity inside Cities with Cell Phone Records</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Gabriel E Kreindler, Yuhei Miyauchi</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Measuring Commuting and Economic Activity inside Cities with Cell Phone Records</dc:title>
<dc:description>We show how to use commuting flows to infer the spatial distribution of income within a city. A simple workplace choice model predicts a gravity equation for commuting flows whose destination fixed effects correspond to wages. We implement this method with cell phone transaction data from Dhaka and Colombo. Model-predicted income predicts separate income data, at the workplace and residential level, and by skill group. Unlike machine learning approaches, our method does not require training data, yet achieves comparable predictive power. We show that hartals (transportation strikes) in Dhaka reduce commuting more for high model-predicted wage and high-skill commuters.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28516</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28516</prism:url></item><item><title>Social and Genetic Effects on Educational Performance in Early Adolescence</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Martin A Isunget, Dalton Conley, Henrik D Zachrisson, Eivind Ystrøm, Alexandra Havdahl, Pål R Njølstad, Torkild H Lyngstad</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Social and Genetic Effects on Educational Performance in Early Adolescence</dc:title>
<dc:description>Research into the intergenerational transmission of educational advantage has long been criticized for not paying sufficient attention to genetics. This study is based on the Norwegian Mother, Father and Child Cohort Study (MoBa) and administrative register data on 25000 genotyped Norwegian children and their parents. We assess and disentangle the relative importance of genetics and social background for children’s standardized academic test scores. Norway offers a particularly interesting context for intergenerational transmission, as the welfare state and educational system is designed to provide equal opportunity structures for children. The results point to genetics only confounding the parent status-offspring achievement relationship to a small degree, to ‘genetic nurture’ effects being small, and pro-vide no evidence of neither Scarr-Rowe interactions in test scores nor parent-child genotype interactions. Even in a universal welfare state with relatively low levels of inequality, there are two systems of ascription, one genetic and one social, and these are largely independent of each other.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28498</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28498</prism:url></item><item><title>Skipping the Bag: The Intended and Unintended Consequences of Disposable Bag Regulation</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Tatiana Homonoff, Lee-Sien Kao, Javiera Selman, Christina Seybolt</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Skipping the Bag: The Intended and Unintended Consequences of Disposable Bag Regulation</dc:title>
<dc:description>Regulation of goods associated with negative environmental externalities may decrease consumption of the targeted product, but may be ineffective at reducing the externality itself if close substitutes are left unregulated. We find evidence that plastic bag bans, the most common disposable bag regulation in the US, led retailers to circumvent the regulation by providing free thicker plastic bags which are not covered by the ban. In contrast, a regulation change that replaced the ban with a small tax on all disposable bags generated large decreases in disposable bag use and overall environmental costs. Our results suggest that narrowly-defined regulations (like plastic bag bans) may be less effective than policies that target a more comprehensive set of products, even in the case when the policy instrument itself (a tax rather than a ban) is not as strict.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28499</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28499</prism:url></item><item><title>A Simple but Powerful Simulated Certainty Equivalent Approximation Method for Dynamic Stochastic Problems</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Yongyang Cai, Kenneth L Judd</dc:creator>
<dc:title>A Simple but Powerful Simulated Certainty Equivalent Approximation Method for Dynamic Stochastic Problems</dc:title>
<dc:description>We introduce a novel simulated certainty equivalent approximation (SCEQ) method for solving dynamic stochastic problems. Our examples show that this method only requires a desktop computer to solve high-dimensional finite- or infinite-horizon, stationary or nonstationary dynamic stochastic problems with hundreds of state variables, a wide state space, and occasionally binding constraints. The SCEQ method is simple, stable, and efficient, which makes it suitable for solving complex economic problems that cannot be solved by other algorithms.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28502</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28502</prism:url></item><item><title>What Marginal Outcome Tests Can Tell Us About Racially Biased Decision-Making</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Peter Hull</dc:creator>
<dc:title>What Marginal Outcome Tests Can Tell Us About Racially Biased Decision-Making</dc:title>
<dc:description>Marginal outcome tests compare the expected effects of a decision on individuals who are of different races but at the same indifference point of the decision-maker. I present a simple formalization of how such tests can detect racial bias, defined as a deviation from accurate statistical discrimination. Namely, the tests can reject that the decision-maker ranks individuals according to some accurate prediction of a mandated outcome, given some unspecified race-inclusive information set. The frontier of marginal effects can furthermore rule out canonical taste-based discrimination. I relate this analysis to other interpretations of marginal outcome tests, other notions of racial discrimination, and recent identification strategies.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28503</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28503</prism:url></item><item><title>Endogenous Immigration, Human and Physical Capital Formation, and the Immigration Surplus</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Isaac Ehrlich, Yun Pei</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Endogenous Immigration, Human and Physical Capital Formation, and the Immigration Surplus</dc:title>
<dc:description>We evaluate the economic consequences of immigration in a two-country, two-skill, overlapping-generations framework, where immigration, population, human and physical capital formation, and economic growth are endogenous variables. We go beyond extant literature by integrating physical capital in our model. This enables the derivation of new insights about the induced-immigration effects of exogenous triggers, including pull and push factors and policy variables, on the dynamic evolution of the “immigration surplus” in the short run versus the long run, in destination vs. source countries and in the global economy. The policy shifts we analyze include the easing of constraints on potential migrants’ labor and physical capital mobility, and the role of physical capital endowments. We also discuss the policy implications of asymmetries in the net benefits from immigration across destination and source countries.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28504</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28504</prism:url></item><item><title>Wages, Minimum Wages, and Price Pass-Through: The Case of McDonald’s Restaurants</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Orley C Ashenfelter, Štěpán Jurajda</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Wages, Minimum Wages, and Price Pass-Through: The Case of McDonald’s Restaurants</dc:title>
<dc:description>We use price and wage data from McDonald&#x27;s restaurants to provide evidence on wage increases, labor-saving technology introduction, and price pass-through by a large low-wage employer facing a flurry of minimum wage hikes from 2016-2020. We estimate an elasticity of hourly wage rates with respect to minimum wages of 0.7. In 40% of instances where minimum wages increase, McDonald&#x27;s restaurants&#x27; wages are near the effective minimum wage level both before and after its increase; however, we also uncover a tendency among a large subset of restaurants to preserve their pay &#x27;premium&#x27; above the minimum wage level. We find no association between the adoption of labor-saving touch screen ordering technology and minimum wage hikes. Our data imply that McDonald&#x27;s restaurants pass through the higher costs of minimum wage increases in the form of higher prices of the Big Mac sandwich. We find a 0.2 price elasticity with respect to wage increases, which implies an elasticity of prices with respect to minimum wages of about 0.14. Based on a listing of all US McDonald&#x27;s restaurants from 2010 to 2020, we also find no effects of minimum wages on McDonald&#x27;s restaurant entry and exit.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28506</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28506</prism:url></item><item><title>In-Kind Transfers as Insurance</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Lucie Gadenne, Samuel Norris, Monica Singhal, Sandip Sukhtankar</dc:creator>
<dc:title>In-Kind Transfers as Insurance</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recent debates about the optimal form of social protection programs have highlighted the potential for cash as the preferred form of transfer to low income households. However, in-kind transfers remain prevalent throughout the world. We argue that beneficiaries themselves may prefer in-kind transfers because these transfers can provide insurance against price risk. Households in developing countries often face substantial price variation as a result of poorly integrated markets. We develop a model demonstrating that in-kind transfers are welfare improving relative to cash if the covariance between the marginal utility of income and price is positive. Using calorie shortfalls as a proxy for marginal utility, we find that in-kind transfers improve welfare relative to cash for Indian households, an effect driven entirely by poor households. We further show that expansions in the generosity of the Public Distribution System (PDS)—India’s in-kind food transfer program—result not only in increased caloric intake but also reduced sensitivity of calories to prices.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28507</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28507</prism:url></item><item><title>Neighborhood Effects and Housing Vouchers</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Morris A Davis, Jesse M Gregory, Daniel A Hartley, Kegon T.K. Tan</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Neighborhood Effects and Housing Vouchers</dc:title>
<dc:description>Researchers and policy-makers have explored the possibility of restricting the use of housing vouchers to neighborhoods that may positively affect the outcomes of children.  Using the framework of a dynamic model of optimal location choice, we estimate preferences over neighborhoods of likely recipients of housing vouchers in Los Angeles.  We combine simulations of the model with estimates of how locations affect adult earnings of children to understand how a voucher policy that restricts neighborhoods in which voucher-recipients may live affects both the location decisions of households and the adult earnings of children.  We show the model can nearly replicate the impact of the Moving to Opportunity experiment on the adult wages of children.  Simulations suggest a policy that restricts housing vouchers to the top 20% of neighborhoods maximizes expected aggregate adult earnings of children of households offered these vouchers.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28508</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28508</prism:url></item><item><title>Whose Job Is It Anyway? Co-Ethnic Hiring in New U.S. Ventures</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Sari Pekkala Kerr, William R Kerr</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Whose Job Is It Anyway? Co-Ethnic Hiring in New U.S. Ventures</dc:title>
<dc:description>We explore co-ethnic hiring among new ventures using U.S. administrative data. Co-ethnic hiring is ubiquitous among immigrant groups, averaging about 22.5% and ranging from &lt;2% to &gt;40%. Co-ethnic hiring grows with the size of the local ethnic workforce, greater linguistic distance to English, lower cultural/genetic similarity to U.S. natives, and in harsher policy environments for immigrants. Co-ethnic hiring is remarkably persistent for ventures and for individuals. Co-ethnic hiring is associated with greater venture survival and growth when thick local ethnic employment surrounds the business. Our results are consistent with a blend of hiring due to information advantages within ethnic groups with some taste-based hiring.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28509</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28509</prism:url></item><item><title>What Explains Differences in Finance Research Productivity During the Pandemic?</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Brad M Barber, Wei Jiang, Adair Morse, Manju Puri, Heather Tookes, Ingrid M Werner</dc:creator>
<dc:title>What Explains Differences in Finance Research Productivity During the Pandemic?</dc:title>
<dc:description>Using a survey of AFA members, we analyze how demographics, time allocation, production mechanisms, and institutional factors affect research production during the pandemic. Consistent with the literature, research productivity falls more for women and faculty with young children. Independently and novel, extra time spent teaching (much more likely for women) negatively affects research productivity. Also novel are the results that concerns about feedback, isolation, and health have large negative research effects, disproportionately affecting junior faculty and PhD students. Finally, faculty facing greater concerns about employers’ finances report larger negative research effects and more concerns about feedback, isolation and health.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28493</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28493</prism:url></item><item><title>Global Pricing of Carbon-Transition Risk</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Patrick Bolton, Marcin Kacperczyk</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Global Pricing of Carbon-Transition Risk</dc:title>
<dc:description>Companies are exposed to carbon-transition risk as the global economy transitions away from fossil fuels to renewable energy. We estimate the market-based premium associated with this transition risk at the firm level in a cross-section of over 14,400 firms in 77 countries. We find a widespread carbon premium—higher stock returns for companies with higher levels of carbon emissions (and higher annual changes)—in all sectors over three continents, Asia, Europe, and North America. Short-term transition risk is greater for firms located in countries with lower economic development, greater reliance on fossil energy, and less inclusive political systems. Long-term transition risk is higher in countries with stricter domestic, but not international, climate policies. However, transition risk cannot be explained by greater exposure to physical (or headline) risk. Yet, raising investor awareness about climate change amplifies the level of transition risk.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28510</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28510</prism:url></item><item><title>The “Matthew Effect” and Market Concentration: Search Complementarities and Monopsony Power</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Jesús Fernández-Villaverde, Federico Mandelman, Yang Yu, Francesco Zanetti</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The “Matthew Effect” and Market Concentration: Search Complementarities and Monopsony Power</dc:title>
<dc:description>This paper develops a dynamic general equilibrium model with heterogeneous firms that face search complementarities in the formation of vendor contracts. Search complementarities amplify small differences in productivity among firms. Market concentration fosters monopsony power in the labor market, magnifying profits and further enhancing high-productivity firms&#x27; output share. Firms want to get bigger and hire more workers, in stark contrast with the classic monopsony model, where a firm aims to reduce the amount of labor it hires. The combination of search complementarities and monopsony power induces a strong “Matthew effect” that endogenously generates superstar firms out of uniform idiosyncratic productivity distributions. Reductions in search costs increase market concentration, lower the labor income share, and increase wage inequality.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28495</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28495</prism:url></item><item><title>The Gendered Impact of the COVID-19 Recession on the US Labor Market</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Stefania Albanesi, Jiyeon Kim</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The Gendered Impact of the COVID-19 Recession on the US Labor Market</dc:title>
<dc:description>The economic crisis associated with the emergence of the novel corona virus is unlike standard recessions. Demand for workers in high contact and inflexible service occupations has declined, while parental supply of labor has been reduced by lack of access to reliable child care and in-person schooling options. This has led to a substantial and persistent drop in employment and labor force participation for women, who are typically less affected by recessions than men. We examine real time data on employment, unemployment, labor force participation and gross job flows to document the gendered impact of the pandemic. We also discuss the potential long-term implications of this crisis, including the role of automation in depressing the recovery of employment for the worst hit service occupations.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28505</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28505</prism:url></item><item><title>Gender and the Dynamics of Economics Seminars</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Pascaline Dupas, Alicia Sasser Modestino, Muriel Niederle, Justin Wolfers, The Seminar Dynamics Collective</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Gender and the Dynamics of Economics Seminars</dc:title>
<dc:description>This paper reports the results of the first systematic attempt at quantitatively measuring the seminar culture within economics and testing whether it is gender neutral. We collected data on every interaction between presenters and their audience in hundreds of research seminars and job market talks across most leading economics departments, as well as during summer conferences. We find that women presenters are treated differently than their male counterparts. Women are asked more questions during a seminar and the questions asked of women presenters are more likely to be patronizing or hostile. These effects are not due to women presenting in different fields, different seminar series, or different topics, as our analysis controls for the institution, seminar series, and JEL codes associated with each presentation. Moreover, it appears that there are important differences by field and that these differences are not uniformly mitigated by more rigid seminar formats. Our findings add to an emerging literature documenting ways in which women economists are treated differently than men, and suggest yet another potential explanation for their under-representation at senior levels within the economics profession.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28494</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28494</prism:url></item><item><title>The Distribution of School Spending Impacts</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>C. Kirabo Jackson, Claire Mackevicius</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The Distribution of School Spending Impacts</dc:title>
<dc:description>We use estimates across all known “credibly causal” studies to examine the distributions of the causal effects of public K12 school spending on test scores and educational attainment in the United States. Under reasonable assumptions, for each of the 31 included studies, we compute the same parameter estimate. Method of moments estimates indicate that, on average, a $1000 increase in per-pupil public school spending (for four years) increases test scores by 0.044 , high-school graduation by 2.1 percentage points, and college-going by 3.9 percentage points. The pooled averages are significant at the 0.0001 level. When benchmarked against other interventions, test score impacts are much smaller than those on educational attainment—suggesting that test-score impacts understate the value of school spending. The benefits to marginal capital spending increases take about five-to-six years to materialize, but after this, are similar to those of non-capital spending increases. The marginal spending impacts are much less pronounced for economically advantaged populations. Consistent with a cumulative effect, the educational attainment impacts are larger with more years of exposure to the spending increase. Average impacts are similar across a wide range of baseline spending levels—providing little evidence of diminishing marginal returns at current spending levels. To speak to generalizability, we estimate the variability across studies attributable to effect heterogeneity (as opposed to sampling variability). This heterogeneity explains about 40 and 70 percent of the variation across studies for educational attainment and test scores, respectively, which allows us to provide a range of likely policy impacts. A policy that increases per-pupil spending for four years will improve test scores 92 percent of the time, and educational attainment even more often. We find suggestive evidence consistent with small possible publication bias, but demonstrate that any effects on our estimates are minimal.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28517</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28517</prism:url></item><item><title>Competition Policy in a Simple General Equilibrium Model</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Louis Kaplow</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Competition Policy in a Simple General Equilibrium Model</dc:title>
<dc:description>The flow of resources across sectors to their best use, with concomitant entry and exit, is central to the functioning and welfare properties of a market economy. Nevertheless, most industrial organization research, including applications to competition policy, undertakes partial equilibrium analysis in a single sector, often with a fixed number of firms. This article examines competition policy in a simple, multi-sector, general equilibrium model with free entry and exit. Even partial equilibrium analysis yields some lessons, such as that accounting for free entry often makes strengthening competition policy more rather than less attractive. When admitting flows between sectors, familiar prescriptions readily reverse. But such results may be partially offset or overturned yet again when incorporating free entry and exit in nontargeted sectors. Finally, the analysis of efficiencies also changes qualitatively with free entry because even fixed costs are fully borne by consumers in equilibrium.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28482</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28482</prism:url></item><item><title>Housing Consumption and the Cost of Remote Work</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Christopher T Stanton, Pratyush Tiwari</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Housing Consumption and the Cost of Remote Work</dc:title>
<dc:description>This paper estimates housing choice differences between households with and without remote workers. Prior to the pandemic, the expenditure share on housing was more than seven percent higher for remote households compared to similar non-remote households in the same commuting zone. Remote households’ higher housing expenditures arise from larger dwellings (more rooms) and a higher price per room. Pre-COVID, households with remote workers were actually located in areas with above-average housing costs, and sorting within-commuting zone to suburban or rural areas was not economically meaningful. Using the pre-COVID distribution of locations, we estimate how much additional pre-tax income would be necessary to compensate non-remote households for extra housing expenses arising from remote work in the absence of geographic mobility, and we compare this compensation to commercial office rents in major metro areas.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28483</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28483</prism:url></item><item><title>Fiscal Policy and Households’ Inflation Expectations: Evidence from a Randomized Control Trial</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Olivier Coibion, Yuriy Gorodnichenko, Michael Weber</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Fiscal Policy and Households’ Inflation Expectations: Evidence from a Randomized Control Trial</dc:title>
<dc:description>Rising government debt levels around the world are raising the specter that authorities might seek to inflate away the debt. In theoretical settings where fiscal policy “dominates” monetary policy, higher debt without offsetting changes in primary surpluses should lead households to anticipate this higher inflation. Are household inflation expectations sensitive to fiscal considerations in practice? We field a large randomized control trial on U.S. households to address this question by providing randomly chosen subsets of households with information treatments about the fiscal outlook and then observing how they revise their expectations about future inflation as well as taxes and government spending. We find that information about the current debt or deficit levels has little impact on inflation expectations but that news about future debt leads them to anticipate higher inflation, both in the short run and long run. News about rising debt also induces households to anticipate rising spending and a higher rate of interest for government debt.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28485</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28485</prism:url></item><item><title>Contractual Rigidity and Political Contestability: Revisiting Public Contract Renegotiations</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Jean Beuve, Marian W Moszoro, Pablo T Spiller</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Contractual Rigidity and Political Contestability: Revisiting Public Contract Renegotiations</dc:title>
<dc:description>We present a model of public procurement in which both contractual flexibility and political tolerance for contractual deviations determine renegotiations. In the model, contractual flexibility allows for adaptation without formal renegotiation while political tolerance for deviations decreases with political competition. We then compare renegotiation rates of procurement contracts in which the procurer is either a public administration or a private corporation. We find robust evidence consistent with the model predictions: public-to-private contracts are renegotiated more often than comparable private-to-private contracts, and that this pattern is more salient in politically contestable jurisdictions. The frequent renegotiation of public contracts results from their inherent rigidity and provides a relational quality of adaptability to contingencies in politically contestable environments.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28491</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28491</prism:url></item><item><title>Aggregate Implications of Barriers to Female Entrepreneurship</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Gaurav Chiplunkar, Pinelopi K Goldberg</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Aggregate Implications of Barriers to Female Entrepreneurship</dc:title>
<dc:description>We develop a framework for identifying and quantifying barriers to entry and operation faced by female entrepreneurs in developing countries, and apply it to the Indian economy. We find that despite considerable progress over time, female entrepreneurs still face substantial entry and business registration costs (almost twice their male counterparts’). The costs of expanding a business, conditional on entry, are also substantially higher for women. However, there is one area in which female entrepreneurs have an advantage: hiring female workers is easier for them. We show that this pattern is not driven by the sectoral composition of female employment. Counterfactual simulations indicate that removing all excess barriers faced by women entrepreneurs would: (a) increase the fraction of female-owned firms significantly (nine times); (b) increase the real wages of female relative to male workers; and (c) generate substantial aggregate productivity and welfare gains (ca. 7% and 18% respectively). These large gains are due to reallocation: low productivity male-owned firms previously sheltered from female competition are replaced by higher productivity female-owned firms previously excluded from the economy.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28486</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28486</prism:url></item><item><title>Kinks as Goals: Accelerating Commissions and the Performance of Sales Teams</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Peter J Kuhn, Lizi Yu</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Kinks as Goals: Accelerating Commissions and the Performance of Sales Teams</dc:title>
<dc:description>We study the performance of small retail sales teams facing an incentive scheme that includes both a lump sum bonus and multiple accelerators (kinks where the piece rate jumps upward). Consistent with standard labor supply models, we find that the presence of an attainable bonus or kink on a work-day raises mean sales, and that sales are highly bunched at the bonus; inconsistent with those models we find that teams bunch at the kinks instead of avoiding them. Teams’ responses to the kinks are consistent with models in which the kinks are perceived as symbolic rewards, and inconsistent with reference point models where kinks induce loss aversion.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28487</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28487</prism:url></item><item><title>Culture, Institutions &amp; the Long Divergence</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Alberto Bisin, Jared Rubin, Avner Seror, Thierry Verdier</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Culture, Institutions &amp; the Long Divergence</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recent theories of the Long Divergence between Middle Eastern and Western European economies focus on Middle Eastern (over-)reliance on religious legitimacy, use of slave soldiers, and persistence of restrictive proscriptions of religious (Islamic) law. These theories take as exogenous the cultural values that complement the prevailing institutions. As a result, they miss the role of cultural values in either supporting the persistence of or inducing change in the economic and institutional environment. In this paper, we address these issues by modeling the joint evolution of institutions and culture. In doing so, we place the various hypotheses of economic divergence into one, unifying framework. We highlight the role that cultural transmission plays in reinforcing institutional evolution toward either theocratic or secular states. We extend the model to shed light on political decentralization and technological change in the two regions.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28488</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28488</prism:url></item><item><title>Preparing for a Pandemic: Accelerating Vaccine Availability</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Amrita Ahuja, Susan Athey, Arthur Baker, Eric Budish, Juan Camilo Castillo, Rachel Glennerster, Scott Duke Kominers, Michael Kremer, Jean Nahrae Lee, Canice Prendergast, Christopher M Snyder, Alex Tabarrok, Brandon Joel Tan, Witold Więcek</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Preparing for a Pandemic: Accelerating Vaccine Availability</dc:title>
<dc:description>Vaccinating the world’s population quickly in a pandemic has enormous health and economic benefits. We analyze the problem faced by governments in determining the scale and structure of procurement for vaccines. We analyze alternative approaches to procurement.  We find that if the goal is to accelerate the vaccine delivery timetable, buyers should directly fund manufacturing capacity and shoulder most of the risk of failure, while maintaining some direct incentives for speed. We analyzed the optimal portfolio of vaccine investments for countries with different characteristics as well as the implications for international cooperation. Our analysis, considered in light of the experience of 2020, suggests lessons for future pandemics.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28492</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28492</prism:url></item><item><title>Do Required Minimum Distribution 401(k) Rules Matter, and For Whom? Insights from a Lifecycle Model</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Vanya Horneff, Raimond Maurer, Olivia S Mitchell</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Do Required Minimum Distribution 401(k) Rules Matter, and For Whom? Insights from a Lifecycle Model</dc:title>
<dc:description>Tax-qualified vehicles helped U.S. private-sector workers accumulate $25Tr in retirement assets. An often-overlooked important institutional feature shaping decumulations from these retirement plans is the “Required Minimum Distribution” (RMD) regulation, requiring retirees to withdraw a minimum fraction from their retirement accounts or pay excise taxes on withdrawal shortfalls. Our calibrated lifecycle model measures the impact of RMD rules on financial behavior of heterogeneous households during their worklives and retirement. We show that proposed reforms to delay or eliminate the RMD rules should have little effects on consumption profiles but more impact on withdrawals and tax payments for households with bequest motives.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28490</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28490</prism:url></item><item><title>Urban Growth Shadows</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>David Cuberes, Klaus Desmet, Jordan Rappaport</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Urban Growth Shadows</dc:title>
<dc:description>Does a location&#x27;s growth benefit or suffer from being geographically close to large economic centers? Spatial proximity may lead to competition and hurt growth, but it may also improve market access and enhance growth. Using data on U.S. counties and metro areas for the period 1840-2017, we document this tradeoff between urban shadows and urban access. Proximity to large urban centers was negatively associated with growth between 1840 and 1920, and positively associated with growth after 1920. Using a two-city spatial model, we show that the secular evolution of inter-city and intra-city commuting costs can account for this. Alternatively, the long-run decline in inter-city shipping costs relative to intra-city commuting costs is also consistent with these observed patterns.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28476</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28476</prism:url></item><item><title>Biases in Information Selection and Processing: Survey Evidence from the Pandemic</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Ester Faia, Andreas Fuster, Vincenzo Pezone, Basit Zafar</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Biases in Information Selection and Processing: Survey Evidence from the Pandemic</dc:title>
<dc:description>How people form beliefs is crucial for understanding decision-making under uncertainty. This is particularly true in a situation such as a pandemic, where beliefs will affect behaviors that impact public health as well as the aggregate economy. We conduct two survey experiments to shed light on potential biases in belief formation, focusing in particular on the tone of information people choose to consume and how they incorporate this information into their beliefs. In the first experiment, people express their preferences over pandemic-related articles with optimistic and pessimistic headlines, and are then randomly shown one of the articles. We find that respondents with more pessimistic prior beliefs about the pandemic are substantially more likely to prefer pessimistic articles, which we interpret as evidence of confirmation bias. In line with this, respondents assigned to the less preferred article rate it as less reliable and informative (relative to those who prefer it); they also discount information from the article when it is less preferred. We further find that these motivated beliefs end up impacting incentivized behavior. In a second experiment, we study how partisan views interact with information selection and processing.  We find strong evidence of source dependence: revealing the news source further distorts information acquisition and processing, eliminating the role of prior beliefs in article choice.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28484</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28484</prism:url></item><item><title>Wage Inequality and Labor Rights Violations</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Ioana Marinescu, Yue Qiu, Aaron Sojourner</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Wage Inequality and Labor Rights Violations</dc:title>
<dc:description>Wage inequality does not fully capture differences in job quality. Jobs also differ along other key dimensions, including the prevalence of labor rights violations. We construct novel measures of labor violation rates using data from federal agencies. Within local industries over time, a 10% increase in the average wage is associated with a 0.15% decrease in the number of violations per employee and a 4% decrease in fines per dollar of pay. Reduced labor market concentration and increased union coverage rate are also associated with reductions in labor violations. Overall, labor violations are regressive: they increase inequality in job quality.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28475</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28475</prism:url></item><item><title>Charter Schools’ Effectiveness, Mechanisms, and Competitive Influence</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Sarah R Cohodes, Katharine S Parham</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Charter Schools’ Effectiveness, Mechanisms, and Competitive Influence</dc:title>
<dc:description>This paper reviews the research on the impacts of charter school attendance on students’ academic and other outcomes, the mechanisms behind those effects, and the influence of charter schools on nearby traditional public schools, almost three decades after the first charter school was established. Across the United States, charter schools appear to perform, on average, at about the same level as their district counterparts. Underlying the similarity in performance across sectors is a consistent finding: charters located in urban areas boost student test scores, particularly for Black, Latinx, and low-income students. Attending some urban charter schools also increases college enrollment and voting and reduces risky behavior, but evidence on such longer-term outcomes has been found in only a few sites and has a limited time horizon. No Excuses charter schools generate test score gains, but their controversial disciplinary practices are not a necessary a condition for academic success. Charter school teachers tend to be less qualified and more likely to leave the profession than traditional public school teachers, though the labor market implications are understudied. The influence of charter authorizers and related accountability structures is also limited and would benefit from more rigorous examination. The competitive impact of charter schools on traditional public schools suggests a small, beneficial influence on neighboring schools’ student achievement, though there is variation across contexts. Charters also appear to induce a negative financial impact for districts, at least in the short term. Finally, there is competing evidence on charters’ contribution to school racial segregation, and little evidence on the impact of newer, intentionally diverse school models. While we know much about charter schools, more research, in more contexts, is needed to further understand where, for whom, and why charters are most effective.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28477</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28477</prism:url></item><item><title>Vertical Integration and Production Inefficiency in the Presence of a Gross Receipts Tax</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Benjamin Hansen, Keaton S Miller, Caroline Weber</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Vertical Integration and Production Inefficiency in the Presence of a Gross Receipts Tax</dc:title>
<dc:description>We quantify the effects of a gross receipts tax (GRT) on vertical integration for the first time. We use data from the Washington state recreational cannabis industry, which has numerous advantages including a clean natural experiment: a 25% GRT imposed on cannabis firms was subsequently replaced by an excise tax at retail. We find the short-run elasticity of vertical integration with respect to the intermediate good net- of-tax rate is -0.15 and the long-run elasticity is more than twice as large. We find these incentives lead to large output losses – production increases by 23 percent when the GRT is eliminated.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28478</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28478</prism:url></item><item><title>Does Private Equity Investment in Healthcare Benefit Patients? Evidence from Nursing Homes</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Atul Gupta, Sabrina T Howell, Constantine Yannelis, Abhinav Gupta</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Does Private Equity Investment in Healthcare Benefit Patients? Evidence from Nursing Homes</dc:title>
<dc:description>The past two decades have seen a rapid increase in Private Equity (PE) investment in healthcare, a sector in which intensive government subsidy and market frictions could lead high-powered for-profit incentives to be misaligned with the social goal of affordable, quality care. This paper studies the effects of PE ownership on patient welfare at nursing homes. With administrative patient-level data, we use a within-facility differences-in-differences design to address non-random targeting of facilities. We use an instrumental variables strategy to control for the selection of patients into nursing homes. Our estimates show that PE ownership increases the short-term mortality of Medicare patients by 10%, implying 20,150 lives lost due to PE ownership over our twelve-year sample period. This is accompanied by declines in other measures of patient well-being, such as lower mobility, while taxpayer spending per patient episode increases by 11%. We observe operational changes that help to explain these effects, including declines in nursing staff and compliance with standards. Finally, we document a systematic shift in operating costs post-acquisition toward non-patient care items such as monitoring fees, interest, and lease payments.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28474</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28474</prism:url></item><item><title>The Two Faces of Information</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Gaetano Gaballo, Guillermo Ordoñez</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The Two Faces of Information</dc:title>
<dc:description>In absence of insurance contracts to share risk, public information is a double-edged sword. On the one hand, it empowers self-insurance as agents better react to shocks, reducing risk. On the other hand, it weakens market-insurance as common knowledge of shocks restricts trading risk. We embody these two faces of information in a single general-equilibrium model. We characterize the conditions under which market-insurance is superior, and then public information – even though costless and precise – is socially undesirable. In the absence of information, however, market-insurance is still underprovided as individuals fail to internalize its general equilibrium benefits.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28489</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28489</prism:url></item><item><title>The Effect of Stock Ownership on Individual Spending and Loyalty</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Paolina C Medina, Vrinda Mittal, Michaela Pagel</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The Effect of Stock Ownership on Individual Spending and Loyalty</dc:title>
<dc:description>In this study, we quantify the effects of receiving stocks from certain brands on spending in the brand&#x27;s stores. We use data from a new FinTech company called Bumped that opens brokerage accounts for its users and rewards them with stocks when they shop at previously elected stores. For identification, we use 1) the staggered distribution of brokerage accounts over time after individuals sign up for a waitlist and 2) randomly distributed stock grants. We find that individuals spend 40% more per week at elected brands and stores after being allocated an account. In response to receiving a stock grant, individuals increase their weekly spending by 100% on the granted brands. Beyond documenting a causal link between stock ownership and individual spending, we show that weekly spending in certain brands of our users is strongly correlated with stock holdings of that brand by Robinhood brokerage clients. Finally, we present survey evidence to argue that loyalty is the dominant psychological mechanism explaining our findings. We thus provide micro evidence for the idea that stock ownership drives brand loyalty, which is an intangible asset that leads to lower firm cash flow volatility.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28479</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28479</prism:url></item><item><title>Cross-sectoral Externalities Related to Natural Resources and Ecosystem Services</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Manuel Bellanger, Robert Fonner, Daniel S Holland, Gary D Libecap, Douglas W Lipton, Pierre Scemama, Cameron Speir, Olivier Thébaud</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Cross-sectoral Externalities Related to Natural Resources and Ecosystem Services</dc:title>
<dc:description>Standard approaches to environmental and natural resource use externalities generally focus on single-sector resources and user groups. Remedies include Pigouvian-style government constraints, small group controls following Elinor Ostrom, or less frequently, bargaining across users as outlined by Ronald Coase. However, many difficult natural resource management problems involve competing uses of the same resource or multiple interdependent resources, across multiple, heterogeneous sectors. Cross-sectoral externalities are generated and impede attainment of conservation objectives. The multiplicity of resources and stakeholders, who may have different property rights, hold different use or non-use values, have different traditions, or fall under different regulatory regimes, increases the likelihood of multi-jurisdictional conflicts. We provide an institutional analysis following Oliver Williamson’s four-levels of institutions (social embeddedness, institutional environment, governance, resource allocation) to illustrate the sources of potential conflict, the costs of addressing them, and the potentials for exchange. In comparing the costs of alternative approaches, we include transaction costs associated with property rights; the costs of lobbying, implementing, and enforcing government regulation; and the costs of scaling up from small-group controls when resource problems involve multiple sectors and heterogeneous populations. In our illustrative case examples, instruments that are not formal property rights are exchanged at lower transaction costs. We close by discussing how Coasean, Pareto-improving voluntary exchange agreements may be lower cost, more effective, and more durable solutions than alternative management regimes to mitigate cross-sectoral externalities.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28480</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28480</prism:url></item><item><title>Searching for Job Security and the Consequences of Job Loss</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Gregor Jarosch</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Searching for Job Security and the Consequences of Job Loss</dc:title>
<dc:description>Job loss comes with large present value earnings losses which elude workhorse models of unemployment and labor market policy. I propose a parsimonious model of a frictional labor market in which jobs differ in terms of unemployment risk and workers search off- and on-the-job. This gives rise to a job ladder with slippery bottom rungs where unemployment spells beget unemployment spells. I allow for human capital to respond to time spent out of work and estimate the framework on German Social Security data. The model captures the joint response of wages, employment, and unemployment risk to job loss which I measure empirically. The key driver of the “unemployment scar” is the loss in job security and its interaction with the evolution of human capital.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28481</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28481</prism:url></item><item><title>Evaluating Contradictory Experimental and Non-Experimental Estimates of Neighborhood Effects on Economic Outcomes for Adults</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>David J Harding, Lisa Sanbonmatsu, Greg J Duncan, Lisa A Gennetian, Lawrence F Katz, Ronald C Kessler, Jeffrey R Kling, Matthew Sciandra, Jens Ludwig</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Evaluating Contradictory Experimental and Non-Experimental Estimates of Neighborhood Effects on Economic Outcomes for Adults</dc:title>
<dc:description>Although non-experimental studies find robust neighborhood effects on adults, such findings have been challenged by results from the Moving to Opportunity (MTO) residential mobility experiment. Using a within-study comparison design, this paper compares experimental and non-experimental estimates from MTO and a parallel analysis of the Panel Study of Income Dynamics (PSID). Striking similarities were found between non-experimental estimates based on MTO and PSID. No clear evidence was found that different estimates are related to duration of adult exposure to disadvantaged neighborhoods, non-linear effects of neighborhood conditions, magnitude of the change in neighborhood context, frequency of moves, treatment effect heterogeneity, or measurement, although uncertainty bands around our estimates were sometimes large. One other possibility is that MTO-induced moves might have been unusually disruptive, but results are inconsistent for that hypothesis. Taken together, the findings suggest that selection bias might account for evidence of neighborhood effects on adult economic outcomes in non-experimental studies.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28454</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28454</prism:url></item><item><title>Aggregate Employment Effects of Unemployment Benefits During Deep Downturns: Evidence from the Expiration of the Federal Pandemic Unemployment Compensation</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Arindrajit Dube</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Aggregate Employment Effects of Unemployment Benefits During Deep Downturns: Evidence from the Expiration of the Federal Pandemic Unemployment Compensation</dc:title>
<dc:description>The expiration of the temporary $600 boost to weekly UI benefits under the Federal Pandemic Unemployment Compensation (FPUC) led to a sharp, unprecedented, 98 percentage point reduction (on average) in the replacement rate during a time when employment was recovering during the Covid recession. Leveraging the considerable variation in this drop across states, I use a difference-in-differences event study design to estimate the macro employment effects. I find little impact of job gains from the benefit reduction, especially when I focus on groups (non-college graduates, and those from non-high-income households) that comprise of most UI recipients. The estimates rule out job gains implied by much of the micro UI duration elasticities from the existing literature.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28470</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28470</prism:url></item><item><title>Auto-Enrollment Retirement Plans for the People: Choices and Outcomes in OregonSaves</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>John Chalmers, Olivia S Mitchell, Jonathan Reuter, Mingli Zhong</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Auto-Enrollment Retirement Plans for the People: Choices and Outcomes in OregonSaves</dc:title>
<dc:description>Oregon recently launched an automatic-enrollment retirement savings program for private sector workers lacking access to other workplace retirement plans. We analyze participation choices, account balances, and inflow/outflow data using administrative records between August 2018 and April 2020. Within the small to mid-sized firms served by OregonSaves, estimated average after-tax earnings are low ($2,365 per month) and turnover rates are high (38.2% per year). Younger employees and employees in larger firms are less likely to opt out, but participation rates fall over time. The most common reason given for opting out is “I can’t afford to save at this time,” but the second most common is “I have my own retirement plan.” As of April 2020, 67,731 accounts had positive account balances, holding $51.1 million in total assets. The average balance is $754, but with considerable dispersion; younger workers accumulating the fewest assets due to higher job turnover. Overall, we conclude that OregonSaves has meaningfully increased employee savings by reducing search costs. The 34.3% of workers with positive account balances in April 2020 is comparable to the marginal increase in participation at larger firms in the private sector. Employees opting out of OregonSaves are often doing so for rational reasons.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28469</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28469</prism:url></item><item><title>Gang rule: Understanding and Countering Criminal Governance</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Christopher Blattman, Gustavo Duncan, Benjamin Lessing, Santiago Tobón</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Gang rule: Understanding and Countering Criminal Governance</dc:title>
<dc:description>Gangs govern millions worldwide. Why rule? And how do they respond to states? Many argue that criminal rule provides protection when states do not, and that increasing state services could crowd gangs out. We began by interviewing leaders from 30 criminal groups in Medellín. The conventional view overlooks gangs’ indirect incentives to rule: governing keeps police out and fosters civilian loyalty, protecting other business lines. We present a model of duopolistic competition with returns to loyalty and show under what conditions exogenous changes to state protection causes gangs to change governance levels. We run the first gang-level field experiment, intensifying city governance in select neighborhoods for two years. We see no decrease in gang rule. We also examine a quasi-experiment. New borders in Medellín created discontinuities in access to government services for 30 years. Gangs responded to greater state rule by governing more. We propose alternatives for countering criminal governance.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28458</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28458</prism:url></item><item><title>The Work-at-Home Technology Boon and its Consequences</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Morris A Davis, Andra C Ghent, Jesse M Gregory</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The Work-at-Home Technology Boon and its Consequences</dc:title>
<dc:description>We study the impact of widespread adoption of work-at-home technology using an equilibrium model where people choose where to live, how to allocate their time between working at home and at the office, and how much space to use in production. A key parameter is the elasticity of substitution between working at home and in the office that we estimate using cross-sectional time-use data. The model indicates that the pandemic induced a large change to the relative productivity of working at home which will permanently affect incomes, income inequality, and city structure.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28461</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28461</prism:url></item><item><title>The Recovery From The Great Recession: A Long, Evolving Expansion</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Jay C Shambaugh, Michael R Strain</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The Recovery From The Great Recession: A Long, Evolving Expansion</dc:title>
<dc:description>Prior to 2020, the Great Recession was the most important macroeconomic shock to the United States economy in generations. Millions lost jobs and homes. At its peak, one in ten workers who wanted a job could not find one. On an annual basis, the economy contracted by more than it had since the Great Depression. A slow and steady recovery followed the Great Recession&#x27;s official end in the summer of 2009, but because it was slow and the depth of the recession so deep, it took years to reduce slack in labor markets. But because the slow-and-steady recovery lasted so long, many pre-recession peaks were exceeded, and eventually real wage growth began to accumulate for workers across the distribution. In fact, the business cycle (including recession and recovery) beginning in December 2007 was one of the better periods of real wage growth in many decades, with the bulk of that coming in the last years of the recovery. We place the Great Recession in historical context and trace the path of the recovery, studying its different phases and how different groups of workers were impacted in each phase. We also discuss the response of fiscal and monetary policy to the Great Recession, and draw lessons for the future.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28452</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28452</prism:url></item><item><title>Does Marijuana Legalization Affect Work Capacity? Evidence from Workers’ Compensation Benefits</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Rahi Abouk, Keshar M Ghimire, Johanna Catherine Maclean, David Powell</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Does Marijuana Legalization Affect Work Capacity? Evidence from Workers’ Compensation Benefits</dc:title>
<dc:description>We study the effect of state recreational marijuana laws (RMLs) on workers’ compensation (WC) benefit receipt among adults 40-62 years. We find that WC receipt declines in response to RML adoption both in terms of the propensity to receive benefits and benefit amount. We estimate complementary declines in non-traumatic workplace injury rates and the incidence of work-limiting disabilities. We offer evidence that the primary driver of these reductions is an improvement in work capacity, likely due to access to an additional form of pain management therapy.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28471</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28471</prism:url></item><item><title>The Social Cost of Carbon, Risk, Distribution, Market Failures: An Alternative Approach</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Nicholas Stern, Joseph E Stiglitz</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The Social Cost of Carbon, Risk, Distribution, Market Failures: An Alternative Approach</dc:title>
<dc:description>Designing policy for climate change requires analyses which integrate the interrelationship between the economy and environment, including: the immense risks and impacts on distribution across and within generations; the many failures, limitations or absences of key markets; and the limitations on government, both in offsetting these failures and distributional impacts. Much of the standard economic modelling, including Integrated Assessment Models, does not embody key aspects of these essentials. We identify fundamental flaws in both the descriptive and normative methodologies commonly used to assess climate policy, showing systematic biases, with costs of climate action overestimated and benefits underestimated. We provide an alternative methodology by which the social cost of carbon may be calculated, one which embraces the essential elements we have identified.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28472</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28472</prism:url></item><item><title>Artificial Intelligence, Globalization, and Strategies for Economic Development</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Anton Korinek, Joseph E Stiglitz</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Artificial Intelligence, Globalization, and Strategies for Economic Development</dc:title>
<dc:description>Progress in artificial intelligence and related forms of automation technologies threatens to reverse the gains that developing countries and emerging markets have experienced from integrating into the world economy over the past half century, aggravating poverty and inequality. The new technologies have the tendency to be labor-saving, resource-saving, and to give rise to winner-takes-all dynamics that advantage developed countries. We analyze the economic forces behind these developments and describe economic policies that would mitigate the adverse effects on developing and emerging economies while leveraging the potential gains from technological advances. We also describe reforms to our global system of economic governance that would share the benefits of AI more widely with developing countries.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28453</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28453</prism:url></item><item><title>Political Violence, Risk Aversion, and Non-Localized Disease Spread: Evidence from the U.S. Capitol Riot</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Dhaval M Dave, Drew McNichols, Joseph J Sabia</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Political Violence, Risk Aversion, and Non-Localized Disease Spread: Evidence from the U.S. Capitol Riot</dc:title>
<dc:description>On January 6, 2021, the U.S. Capitol was sieged by rioters protesting certification of Joseph R. Biden’s election as the 46th president of the United States. The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) quickly predicted that the Riot would be a COVID-19 “surge event.” This study is the first to estimate the impact of the Capitol Riot on risk-averting behavior and community-level spread of the novel coronavirus. First, using anonymized smartphone data from SafeGraph, Inc. and an event-study approach, we document that on January 6th there was a substantial increase in non-resident smartphone pings in the census block groups including the Ellipse, the National Mall, and the U.S. Capitol Building, consistent with a large protest that day. Next, using data from the same source and a synthetic control approach, we find that the Capitol Riot increased stay-at-home behavior among District of Columbia residents, indicative of risk averting behaviors in response to violence and health risks. Finally, turning to COVID-19 case data, we find no evidence that the Capitol Riot substantially increased community spread of COVID-19 in the District of Columbia in the month-long period following the event. This may be due to increases in social distancing and a “virtual lockdown” of the Capitol prior to the inauguration of the new president. However, exploiting variation in non-resident smartphone inflows into the January 6 Capitol protest, we find that counties with the highest protester inflows experienced a significant increase in the rate of daily cumulative COVID-19 case growth in the month following the protest. We conclude that the Capitol Riot may have contributed to non-localized COVID-19 spread.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28410</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28410</prism:url></item><item><title>To What Extent Does In-Person Schooling Contribute to the Spread of COVID-19? Evidence from Michigan and Washington</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Dan Goldhaber, Scott A Imberman, Katharine O Strunk, Bryant Hopkins, Nate Brown, Erica Harbatkin, Tara Kilbride</dc:creator>
<dc:title>To What Extent Does In-Person Schooling Contribute to the Spread of COVID-19? Evidence from Michigan and Washington</dc:title>
<dc:description>The decision about how and when to open schools to in-person instruction has been a key question for policymakers throughout the COVID-19 pandemic. The instructional modality of schools has implications not only for the health and safety of students and staff, but also student learning and the degree to which parents can engage in job activities. We consider the role of instructional modality (in-person, hybrid, or remote instruction) in disease spread among the wider community. Using a variety of regression modeling strategies , we find that simple correlations show in-person modalities are correlated with increased COVID cases, but accounting for both pre-existing cases and a richer set of covariates brings estimates close to zero on average. In Ordinary Least Squares (OLS) specifications, in-person modality options are not associated with increased spread of COVID at low levels of pre-existing COVID cases but cases do increase at moderate to high pre-existing COVID rates. A bounding exercise suggests that the OLS findings for in-person modality are likely to represent an upper bound on the true relationship. These findings are robust to the inclusion of county and district fixed effects in terms of the insignificance of the findings, but the models with fixed effects are also somewhat imprecisely estimated.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28455</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28455</prism:url></item><item><title>Sticky Price for Declining Risk? The Case of Cancellation Premia in the Hotel Industry</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Nicola Lacetera, Claudio A Piga, Lorenzo Zirulia</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Sticky Price for Declining Risk? The Case of Cancellation Premia in the Hotel Industry</dc:title>
<dc:description>Using data from about seven millions room postings by hotels in France and the UK, we document that, rather than smoothly decreasing to zero, cancellation premia remain positive at roughly 10% to 15% of the full price until two days before the stay. A model where travelers have different willingness to pay and some overestimate the probability to cancel their trip explains this price-setting mode more consistently than alternative interpretations. We denote these strategies as a form of naivet�-based price discrimination. We use our model also to identify conditions under which these strategies are exploitative of certain consumers, or are welfare-enhancing instead.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28456</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28456</prism:url></item><item><title>Reparations and Persistent Racial Wealth Gaps</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Job Boerma, Loukas Karabarbounis</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Reparations and Persistent Racial Wealth Gaps</dc:title>
<dc:description>Reparations is a policy proposal aiming to address the wealth gap between Black and White households. We provide a first formal analysis of the economics of reparations using a long-run model of heterogeneous dynasties with an occupational choice and bequests. Our innovation is to introduce endogenous dispersion of beliefs about risky returns, reflecting differences in dynasties&#x27; experiences with entrepreneurship over time. Feeding the exclusion of Black dynasties from labor and capital markets as driving force, the model quantitatively reproduces current and historical racial gaps in wealth, income, entrepreneurship, mobility, and beliefs about risky returns. We use the model to evaluate reparations and find that transfers eliminating the racial gap in average wealth today do not lead to wealth convergence in the long run. The logic is that century-long exclusions lead Black dynasties to enter into reparations with pessimistic beliefs about risky returns and to forego investment opportunities. We conclude by showing that entrepreneurial subsidies are more effective than wealth transfers in achieving racial wealth convergence in the long run.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28468</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28468</prism:url></item><item><title>Getting the Price Right? The Impact of Competitive Bidding in the Medicare Program</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Hui Ding, Mark Duggan, Amanda Starc</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Getting the Price Right? The Impact of Competitive Bidding in the Medicare Program</dc:title>
<dc:description>We study Medicare&#x27;s competitive bidding program (CBP) for durable medical equipment (DME). We exploit Medicare claims data to examine both prices and utilization, focusing on continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP) devices to treat sleep apnea. We find that spending falls by 47.2% percent after a highly imperfect bidding mechanism is introduced. The effect is almost entirely driven by a 44.8% price reduction, though quantities also fall by 4.3%. To disentangle supply and demand, we leverage differential cost sharing across Medicare recipients. We measure a demand elasticity of -0.272 and find that quantity reductions are concentrated among less clinically appropriate groups.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28457</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28457</prism:url></item><item><title>A Division of Laborers: Identity and Efficiency in India</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Guilhem Cassan, Daniel Keniston, Tatjana Kleineberg</dc:creator>
<dc:title>A Division of Laborers: Identity and Efficiency in India</dc:title>
<dc:description>Workers&#x27; social identity affects their choice of occupation, and therefore the structure and prosperity of the aggregate economy. We study this phenomenon in a setting where work and identity are particularly intertwined: the Indian caste system. Using a new dataset that combines information on caste, occupation, wages, and historical evidence of subcastes’ traditional occupations, we show that caste members are still greatly overrepresented in their traditional occupations. To quantify the effects of caste-level distortions on aggregate and distributional outcomes, we develop a general equilibrium Roy model of occupational choice. We structurally estimate the model and evaluate counterfactuals in which we remove castes&#x27; ties to their traditional occupations: both through their direct preferences, and also via their parental occupations and social networks. We find that the share of workers employed in their traditional occupation decreases substantially. However, effects on aggregate output and productivity are very small–and in some counterfactuals even negative–because gains from a more efficient human capital allocation are offset by productivity losses from weaker caste networks and reduced learning across generations. Our findings emphasize the importance of caste identity in coordinating workers into occupational networks which enable productivity spillovers.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28462</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28462</prism:url></item><item><title>Gender Quotas and Support for Women in Board Elections</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Marina Gertsberg, Johanna Mollerstrom, Michaela Pagel</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Gender Quotas and Support for Women in Board Elections</dc:title>
<dc:description>We study shareholder support for corporate board nominees in the context of the California gender quota, which was passed in 2018. Using hand-collected data for approximately 600 firms, we show that, prior to the quota, female nominees received greater shareholder support than their male counterparts. This is consistent with a pre-quota environment in which female board nominees were held to a higher standard than male nominees. Second, we show that incumbent female directors in the post-quota environment receive greater support than incumbent men, while support for new (mandated) female nominees decreases to the level of support for new male nominees. This indicates that the quota led to a conversion in the bar for men and women to become board nominees, and that it did not lead to new female board nominees being of lower quality than male nominees. We likewise challenge the notion that the negative stock price reaction to the quota reflects value destruction due to an insufficient supply of female directors. Instead, we provide evidence that dysfunctional board dynamics are driving the reaction, in the sense that stock prices reacted negatively to entrenched boards who failed to turn over the least supported directors when adjusting their boards to comply with the new law.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28463</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28463</prism:url></item><item><title>The Analytic Theory of a Monetary Shock</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Fernando E Alvarez, Francesco Lippi</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The Analytic Theory of a Monetary Shock</dc:title>
<dc:description>We propose an analytical method to analyze the propagation of a once-and-for-all shock in a broad class of sticky price models. The method is based on the eigenvalue- eigenfunction representation of the dynamics of the cross-sectional distribution of firms’ desired adjustments. A key novelty is that, under assumptions that are appropriate for low-inflation economies, we can approximate the whole profile of the impulse response for any moment of interest in response to an aggregate shock (any displacement of the invariant distribution). We present several applications and discuss extensions.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28464</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28464</prism:url></item><item><title>Learning from Shared News: When Abundant Information Leads to Belief Polarization</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Renee Bowen, Danil Dmitriev, Simone Galperti</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Learning from Shared News: When Abundant Information Leads to Belief Polarization</dc:title>
<dc:description>We study learning via shared news. Each period agents receive the same quantity and quality of first-hand information and can share it with friends. Some friends (possibly few) share selectively, generating heterogeneous news diets across agents akin to echo chambers. Agents are aware of selective sharing and update beliefs by Bayes’ rule. Contrary to standard learning results, we show that beliefs can diverge in this environment leading to polarization. This requires that (i) agents hold misperceptions (even minor) about friends&#x27; sharing and (ii) information quality is sufficiently low. Polarization can worsen when agents&#x27; social connections expand. When the quantity of first-hand information becomes large, agents can hold opposite extreme beliefs resulting in severe polarization. Our results hold without media bias or fake news, so eliminating these is not sufficient to reduce polarization. When fake news is included, we show that it can lead to polarization but only through misperceived selective sharing. News aggregators can curb polarization caused by shared news.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28465</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28465</prism:url></item><item><title>Asymmetric Information and Sovereign Debt: Theory Meets Mexican Data</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Harold L Cole, Daniel Neuhann, Guillermo Ordoñez</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Asymmetric Information and Sovereign Debt: Theory Meets Mexican Data</dc:title>
<dc:description>Using a novel data set containing all bids by all bidders for Mexican government bonds from 2001 to 2017, we demonstrate that asymmetric information about default risk is a key determinant of primary market bond yields.  Empirically, large bidders do not pay more for bonds than the average bidder but their bids are accepted more frequently. We construct a model where investors may differ in wealth, risk aversion, market power and information, and find that only heterogeneous information can qualitatively account for these patterns. Moreover, asymmetric information about rare disasters can quantitatively match key moments of bids and yields, both within and across periods.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28459</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28459</prism:url></item><item><title>The Economic Geography of Global Warming</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Jose Luis Cruz Alvarez, Esteban Rossi-Hansberg</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The Economic Geography of Global Warming</dc:title>
<dc:description>Global warming is a worldwide and protracted phenomenon with heterogeneous local economic effects. In order to evaluate the aggregate and local economic consequences of higher temperatures, we propose a dynamic economic assessment model of the world economy with high spatial resolution. Our model features a number of mechanisms through which individuals can adapt to global warming, including costly trade and migration, and local technological innovations and natality rates. We quantify the model at a 1° × 1° resolution and estimate damage functions that determine the impact of temperature changes on a region’s fundamental productivity and amenities depending on local temperatures. Our baseline results show welfare losses as large as 15% in parts of Africa and Latin America but also high heterogeneity across locations, with northern regions in Siberia, Canada, and Alaska experiencing gains. Our results indicate large uncertainty about average welfare effects and point to migration and, to a lesser extent, innovation as important adaptation mechanisms. We use the model to assess the impact of carbon taxes, abatement technologies, and clean energy subsidies. Carbon taxes delay consumption of fossil fuels and help flatten the temperature curve but are much more effective when an abatement technology is forthcoming.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28466</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28466</prism:url></item><item><title>China’s War on Pollution: Evidence from the First Five Years</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Michael Greenstone, Guojun He, Shanjun Li, Eric Zou</dc:creator>
<dc:title>China’s War on Pollution: Evidence from the First Five Years</dc:title>
<dc:description>The decade from 2010 to 2019 marked a significant turning point in China’s history of environmental regulation and pollution. This article describes the recent trends in air and water quality, with a focus on the five years since China declared a “war on pollution” in 2014. It summarizes the emerging literature that has taken advantage of accompanying improvements in data availability and accuracy to document sharp improvements in environmental quality, especially local air pollution, and understand their social, economic, and health consequences.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28467</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28467</prism:url></item><item><title>The Price and Quantity of Interest Rate Risk</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Jennifer N Carpenter, Fangzhou Lu, Robert F Whitelaw</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The Price and Quantity of Interest Rate Risk</dc:title>
<dc:description>Studies of the dynamics of bond risk premia that do not account for the corresponding dynamics of bond risk are hard to interpret. We propose a new approach to modeling bond risk and risk premia.  For each of the US and China, we reduce the government bond market to its first two principal-component bond-factor portfolios.  For each bond-factor portfolio, we estimate the joint dynamics of its volatility and Sharpe ratio as functions of yield curve variables, and of VIX in the US. We have three main findings. (1) There is an important second factor in bond risk premia. (2) Time variation in bond return volatility is as important as time variation in bond Sharpe ratios. (3) Bond risk premia are solely compensation for bond risk, as no-arbitrage theory predicts. Our approach also allows us to document interesting cyclical and secular time-variation in the term structure of bond risk premia in both the US and China.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28444</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28444</prism:url></item><item><title>Unemployment in the Time of COVID-19: A Flow-Based Approach to Real-time Unemployment Projections</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Ayşegül Şahin, Murat Tasci, Jin Yan</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Unemployment in the Time of COVID-19: A Flow-Based Approach to Real-time Unemployment Projections</dc:title>
<dc:description>This paper presents a flow-based methodology for real-time unemployment rate projections and shows that this approach performed considerably better at the onset of the COVID-19 recession in the spring 2020 in predicting the peak unemployment rate as well as its rapid decline over the year. It presents an alternative scenario analysis for 2021 based on this methodology and argues that the unemployment rate is likely to decline to 5.4 percent by the end of 2021. The predictive power of the methodology comes from its combined use of real-time data with the flow approach.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28445</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28445</prism:url></item><item><title>Data-Driven Incentive Alignment in Capitation Schemes</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Mark Braverman, Sylvain Chassang</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Data-Driven Incentive Alignment in Capitation Schemes</dc:title>
<dc:description>This paper explores whether Big Data, taking the form of extensive high dimensional records, can reduce the cost of adverse selection by private service providers in government-run capitation schemes, such as Medicare Advantage. We argue that using data to improve the ex ante precision of capitation regressions is unlikely to be helpful. Even if types become essentially observable, the high dimensionality of covariates makes it infeasible to precisely estimate the cost of serving a given type: Big Data makes types observable, but not necessarily interpretable. This gives an informed private operator scope to select types that are relatively cheap to serve. Instead, we argue that data can be used to align incentives by forming unbiased and non-manipulable ex post estimates of a private operator’s gains from selection.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28429</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28429</prism:url></item><item><title>Time Aggregation in Health Insurance Deductibles</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Long Hong, Corina Mommaerts</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Time Aggregation in Health Insurance Deductibles</dc:title>
<dc:description>Health insurance plans increasingly pay for expenses only beyond a large annual deductible. This paper explores the implications of deductibles that reset over shorter timespans. We develop a model of insurance demand between two actuarially equivalent deductible policies, in which one deductible is larger and resets annually and the other deductible is smaller and resets biannually. Our model incorporates borrowing constraints, moral hazard, mid-year contract switching, and delayable care. Calibrations using claims data show that the liquidity benefits of resetting deductibles can generate welfare gains of 6-10% of premium costs, particularly for individuals with borrowing constraints.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28430</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28430</prism:url></item><item><title>Man Versus Machine? Self-Reports Versus Algorithmic Measurement of Publications</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Xuan Jiang, Wan-Ying Chang, Bruce A Weinberg</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Man Versus Machine? Self-Reports Versus Algorithmic Measurement of Publications</dc:title>
<dc:description>This paper uses newly available data from Web of Science on publications matched to researchers in Survey of Doctorate Recipients to compare scientific publications collected by surveys and algorithmic approaches. We aim to illustrate the different types of measurement errors in self-reported and machine-generated data by estimating how publication measures from the two approaches are related to career outcomes (e.g. salaries, placements, and faculty rankings). We find that the potential biases in the self-reports are smaller relative to the algorithmic data. Moreover, the errors in the two approaches are quite intuitive: the measurement errors of the algorithmic data are mainly due to the accuracy of matching, which primarily depends on the frequency of names and the data that was available to make matches; while the noise in self reports is expected to increase over the career as researchers’ publication records become more complex, harder to recall, and less immediately relevant for career progress. This paper provides methodological suggestion on evaluating the quality and advantages of two approaches to data construction. It also provides guidance on how to use the new linked data.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28431</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28431</prism:url></item><item><title>The Health Costs of Cost-Sharing</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Amitabh Chandra, Evan Flack, Ziad Obermeyer</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The Health Costs of Cost-Sharing</dc:title>
<dc:description>We use the design of Medicare’s prescription drug benefit program to demonstrate three facts about the health consequences of cost-sharing. First, we show that an as-if-random increase of 33.6% in out-of-pocket price (11.0 percentage points (p.p.) change in coinsurance, or $10.40 per drug) causes a 22.6% drop in total drug consumption ($61.20), and a 32.7% increase in monthly mortality (0.048 p.p.). Second, we trace this mortality effect to cutbacks in life-saving medicines like statins and antihypertensives, for which clinical trials show large mortality benefits. We find no indication that these reductions in demand affect only ‘low-value’ drugs; on the contrary, those at the highest risk of heart attack and stroke, who would benefit the most from statins and antihypertensives, cut back more on these drugs than lower risk patients. Similar patterns exist for other drug–disease pairs, and irrespective of socioeconomic circumstance. Finally, we document that when faced with complex, high-dimensional choice problems, patients respond in simple, perverse ways. Specifically, price increases cause 18.0% more patients (2.8 p.p.) to fill no drugs, regardless of how many drugs they had been on previously, or their health risks. This decision mechanically results in larger absolute reductions in utilization for those on many drugs. We conclude that cost-sharing schemes should be evaluated based on their overall impact on welfare, which can be very different from the price elasticity of demand.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28439</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28439</prism:url></item><item><title>Is There A Replication Crisis In Finance?</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Theis Ingerslev Jensen, Bryan T Kelly, Lasse Heje Pedersen</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Is There A Replication Crisis In Finance?</dc:title>
<dc:description>Several papers argue that financial economics faces a replication crisis because the majority of studies cannot be replicated or are the result of multiple testing of too many factors. We develop and estimate a Bayesian model of factor replication, which leads to different conclusions. The majority of asset pricing factors: (1) can be replicated, (2) can be clustered into 13 themes, the majority of which are significant parts of the tangency portfolio, (3) work out-of-sample in a new large data set covering 93 countries, and (4) have evidence that is strengthened (not weakened) by the large number of observed factors.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28432</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28432</prism:url></item><item><title>A Parsimonious Behavioral SEIR Model of the 2020 COVID Epidemic in the United States and the United Kingdom</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Andrew Atkeson</dc:creator>
<dc:title>A Parsimonious Behavioral SEIR Model of the 2020 COVID Epidemic in the United States and the United Kingdom</dc:title>
<dc:description>I present a behavioral epidemiological model of the evolution of the COVID epidemic in the United States and the United Kingdom over the past 12 months. The model includes the introduction of a new, more contagious variant in the UK in early fall and the US in mid December. The model is behavioral in that activity, and thus transmission, responds endogenously to the daily death rate. I show that with only seasonal variation in the transmission rate and pandemic fatigue modeled as a one-time reduction in the semi-elasticity of the transmission rate to the daily death rate late in the year, the model can reproduce the evolution of daily and cumulative COVID deaths in the both countries from Feb 15, 2020 to the present remarkably well. I find that most of the end-of-year surge in deaths in both the US and the UK was generated by pandemic fatigue and not the new variant of the virus. I then generate fore- casts for the evolution of the epidemic over the next two years with continuing seasonality, pandemic fatigue, and spread of the new variant.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28434</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28434</prism:url></item><item><title>The Unholy Trinity: Regulatory Forbearance, Stressed Banks and Zombie Firms</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Anusha Chari, Lakshita Jain, Nirupama Kulkarni</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The Unholy Trinity: Regulatory Forbearance, Stressed Banks and Zombie Firms</dc:title>
<dc:description>During the global financial crisis, the Reserve Bank of India enacted forbearance measures that lowered capital provisioning rates for loans under temporary liquidity stress. Matched bank-firm data reveal that troubled banks took advantage of the policy to also shield firms facing serious solvency issues. Perversely, in industries and bank portfolios with high proportions of failing firms, credit to healthy firms declined and was reallocated to the weakest firms. By incentivizing banks to hide true asset quality, the forbearance policy provided a license for regulatory arbitrage. The build-up of stressed assets in India’s predominantly state-owned banking system is consistent with accounting subterfuge.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28435</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28435</prism:url></item><item><title>Using Monotonicity Restrictions to Identify Models with Partially Latent Covariates</title>
<description>teste</description>
<dc:creator>Minji Bang, Wayne Gao, Andrew Postlewaite, Holger Sieg</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Using Monotonicity Restrictions to Identify Models with Partially Latent Covariates</dc:title>
<dc:description>This paper develops a new method for identifying econometric models with partially latent covariates. Such data structures arise naturally in industrial organization and labor economics settings where data are collected using an “input-based sampling” strategy, e.g., if the sampling unit is one of multiple labor input factors. We show that the latent covariates can be nonparametrically identified, if they are functions of a common shock satisfying some plausible monotonicity assumptions. With the latent covariates identified, semiparametric estimation of the outcome equation proceeds within a standard IV framework that accounts for the endogeneity of the covariates. We illustrate the usefulness of our method using two applications. The first focuses on pharmacies: we find that production function differences between chains and independent pharmacies may partially explain the observed transformation of the industry structure. Our second application investigates education achievement functions and illustrates important differences in child investments between married and divorced couples.</dc:description>
<prism:doi>10.3386/w28436</prism:doi>
<prism:url>http://www.nber.org/papers/w28436</prism:url></item></channel></rss>